(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-23T09:12:02.046692",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
扉開ければ
When I open the door,
ねじれた昼の夜
it's a twisted night during noon.
昨日どうやって帰った
How did I get home yesterday?
体だけが確か
My body is the only thing I'm sure of.
おはよう これから
Good morning, from here on out,
また迷子の続き
I'll continue being lost again,
見慣れた知らない景色の中で
amidst an unfamiliar scenery I'd grown so used to.
もう駄目って思ってから
Since the moment I thought all was lost,
割となんだかやれている
I've somehow managed quite well.
死にきらないくらいに大丈夫
I'm fine enough not to die,
何かちょっと恥ずかしい
though it's a bit embarrassing.
やるべきことは 忘れていても解る
I know what I must do, even if I forget,
そうしないと とても苦しいから
because otherwise it would be so painful.
顔を上げて 黒い目の人
Raise your head, you with the black eyes.
君が見たから 光は生まれた
It was because you saw it that light was born.
選んだ色で塗った世界に囲まれて
Surrounded by a world painted in colors of my choosing,
選べない傷の意味はどこだろう
Where is the meaning in the wounds I cannot choose?
ご自分だけがヒーロー 世界の真ん中で
The sole hero of yourself, in the center of the world,
終わるまで出っ張り続き ステージの上
standing out on top of the stage until it ends.
どうしよう 空っぽのふりも出来ない
What can I do? I can't even pretend to be empty.
ハロー、どうも、僕はここ
Hello, hey there, I'm right here.
覚えてしまった感覚 思い出とは違う類
A feeling I've remembered, different from memories,
もっと涙の側にあって いつも心臓掴まれてて
closer to tears, always gripping my heart,
充分理解出来ている ずっとそれと一緒
I understand it completely, always being with it.
そうじゃないと 何も見えないから
Otherwise, I wouldn't be able to see anything at all.
息を繋ぐ 生きる強い人
Connecting our breath, a strong person living.
止まる心を 引き摺って連れてきた
Dragging along a heart that wanted to stop.
塞いだ耳で聴いた 虹の様なメロディー
A rainbow-like melody heard with blocked ears,
砕けない思いが内側で歌う
an unbreakable feeling sings on the inside.
隠れていたってヒーロー 守るものがある
A hero even while hiding, with something to protect.
恐いのは それほど気付いているから
You're afraid because you realize that much.
扉開ければ ねじれた本当の嘘
When I open the door, it's a twisted true lie,
空っぽのふりのふり 体だけが確か
pretending to pretend to be empty, my body is the only sure thing.
おはよう 今でも まだ最後の続き
Good morning, even now, it's still the continuation of the end.
叫ぼう そこから
Let's shout from there,
さあ 扉を開けて
Now, open the door,
君は強い人
You are a strong person,
その目が見たから
because those eyes saw it.
すべては生まれた
Everything was born.
選んだ色で塗った
Painted in the color you chose,
世界に囲まれて
surrounded by the world,
選べない傷の意味はどこだろう
I wonder what unchosen scars mean.
ご自分だけがヒーロー
You are your own hero,
世界の真ん中で
in the center of the world.
怖いのはその価値も知っているから
What's scary is knowing its value.
塞いだ耳で訊いた
Heard with blocked ears,
虹のようなメロディ
a melody like a rainbow.
砕けない思いが内側で歌う
Unbreakable feelings sing within.
悲鳴を上げたヒーロー
A hero who raised a scream,
世界の真ん中で終わるまで出っ張り
standing out in the world's center.
自分が見てるだからもう
You see yourself, so already...
死んだふりも意味ない
even playing dead is meaningless.
ハロー どうも 僕はここ
Hello, hello, I am right here.
はーい！というわけで、
Hii! So,
みなさまこんばんは、こんねね！
everyone, good evening, Konnene!
ホロライブ5期生、オレンジ担当、
Hololive 5th Generation, orange rep,
アイドルVTuberの桃鈴ねねです！
idol VTuber Momosuzu Nene!
いぇーい！みんな元気？やっほー！
Yay! Is everyone well? Yahoo!
んーーまっ、まっ、まっ、まっ、まっ！
Mwah, mwah, mwah, mwah, mwah!
えー、というわけで、今1曲目、
Uh, so, right now for the first song,
あの、バンプさんの「Hello,world!」をお聴きいただきました！
um, you listened to Bump's "Hello,world!"!
はあ、ちょっとだけ緊張しちゃったなー、はあー。
Phew, I got a little nervous, phew.
え、ちょっと、のど調整します。
Uh, let me adjust my throat for a sec.
はい、というわけで、えー、本日、
Yes, so, um, today—
あ、本日じゃないね、8月に2周年を迎えまして、
well, not today, we welcomed our 2nd anniversary in August,
えっと、ちょっと遅れちゃったんですけど、10月になっちゃったんですけど、
and um, it got a bit delayed to October,
今日2周年の お祝いさせていただけて、よろしくお願いしまーす！
but I'm so glad we can celebrate today, thank you so much!
今日のはっしゅたぐはこちらです！
Today's hashtag is right here!
桃鈴ねね2周年、そのままだからね、
#MomosuzuNene2ndAnniversary, it's just that,
そのままでいっぱいいいと…いっぱいいいとじゃない、
so please—not tweet good, tweet a lot—
猫舌の人も今日くらいツイートいかがですか？
Even those not big on tweeting, how about tweeting today?
たまにはいいでしょう！
That's fine sometimes, right?
え、して、いっぱいしてくださいね。
Um, do it lots, okay?
スクショいっぱい撮っててくださいね。
Take lots of screenshots, okay?
ねね動くから、ちょっとスクショの難易度が高いと思うけど、
Nene moves, so screenshot difficulty is high,
みんなならできるよね？プロのスクショリストならできるはずなん
but everyone can do it, right? Pro screenshotters should be able to.
あの、撮れるもんなら撮ってみてください！
Um, try taking them if you can!
はーい、というわけで、あの、ちょっと休憩いいかな？
Hii, so, um, can I take a little break?
疲れちゃったよ。
I got tired.
息が詰まって。
I'm running out of breath.
いや、なんか、あのステージに、あの、こうやって立つのは久しぶりな気がします。
Man, like, standing on that stage like this feels like it's been a while.
見てください、ステージ！かわいいでしょ？
Look at it, the stage! Isn't it cute?
めの、ね、熊の時の一緒の耳がついてて、
Nene's, you know, it has the same bear ears,
ねねの頭のお花もついてて、超かわいいんだからー！
and Nene's head flowers are attached too, it's super cute!
さてさてさて、次に行く前に、今ね、ちょっと1曲目から本気出しすぎちゃって、
Now, before going to the next song, since I went too all-out from song 1,
あの、暑いのね、上着を脱いできたいと思います。ちょっとね、
um, it's hot, so I'm gonna take off my jacket. Um,
上着を脱ぐだけとはいえ、女の子の生着替えを見せるわけにはいきませんので、
though it's just taking off a jacket, I can't show a girl changing clothes live,
少しだけ皆さんお待ちください。
so everyone please wait just a moment.
それじゃあ、上着…
So, jacket...
ばっ！
bam!
おらー！ちゃーん！
Ora! Chan!
みんな見ないで！生肌見ないでください！やめてください！
Everyone, don't look! Don't look at my bare skin! Please stop!
はい、というわけで、あの、ちょっと次の曲、まだ始まったばかりですので、
Yes, so, um, for the next song, it's still just beginning,
みんなガヤガヤ行こぜー！
so let's all get lively!
と、いうわけで、次の曲いっちゃおうかなー！
So, shall we go to the next song?
音大丈夫かな？心配だけどまあいいか。
Is the sound okay? I'm worried, but oh well.
といいうわけで、次の曲いってみましょう！それでは2曲目聴いてください、「世界」！
Well then, let's go to the next song! Alright, please listen to the 2nd song, "Sekai"!
ずっと探してたんだよ
I've always been searching,
特別だって言える場所
for a special place.
なんで僕を選んだの
Why did you choose me?
笑うキミが手を引いたんだ
You took my hand with a smile.
だってキミはすごいから
Because you are so amazing,
負けないんだって思うんだよ
I feel like I can't lose either.
どんな時も僕の中に
No matter what, inside of me
キミの声が鳴り響いていた
Your voice was ringing out.
怖いんだ
I'm scared,
なにもない僕だけどできるかな
I have nothing, but can I do it?
自信のなさとかしょうもなさでいい勝負さ
With my lack of confidence and triviality, it's a fair match,
だけど キミは「それがどうしたの?」って顔して
But you make a face like "So what?"
歌を歌うじゃない それはズルいじゃない
And sing a song—isn't that unfair?
飛び込んでいこう 僕らのセカイへ
Let's dive into our world,
正解の想いに出会えるかな
I wonder if we can find the right feelings?
歌っていたい 踊っていたい
I want to keep singing, keep dancing,
痛いくらい笑えるように
So that I can laugh until it hurts.
名前もない 僕らのセカイを
This nameless world of ours,
迷っていけるよ キミとだから
I can wander through, because I'm with you.
変わっていこう 願うように
Let's change, just as we wish,
今僕ら 期待の未体験を
Right now, let's experience the expected unknown.
キミの未来を僕が歌うよ 描いてもっと Yeah
I'll sing your future, let's draw it out even more, yeah!
泣いてもいいじゃん それも答えだ どうしたっていいよ
It's okay to cry, that's an answer too, however you want is fine.
想いは全部 零さぬように 抱き締めながら
Holding onto all these feelings so none of them spill,
キミと見たセカイへ
To the world I saw with you.
ずっと探してたんだよ
I've always been searching,
特別だって言える場所
Searching for a place I can call special.
どんな僕になるんだろう
I wonder what kind of me I'll become?
踊るココロ変えないように
So that my dancing heart doesn't change.
ちょっとだけのその先で また笑えるよ
Just a little bit beyond that, we can smile again.
もらったバトンは勇気に
The baton I received becomes courage,
ありがとうは歌声に
And my "thank you" becomes a song.
気付いたんだ
I realized
僕にしか出来ないこともあること 誰かのことへ ちゃんと歌を届けたいのさ
That there are things only I can do, and I want to properly deliver my song to someone.
ほら 怖くて震える手でビート刻めば
Look, if you tap the beat with trembling hands,
夢も近いうじゃない? 僕らひとりじゃない
Your dream isn't far away, is it? We are not alone.
飛び込んでいこう 僕らのセカイへ
Let's dive into our world,
正解の想いに出会えるかな
I wonder if we can find the right feelings?
歌っていたい 踊っていたい
I want to keep singing, keep dancing,
痛いくらい笑えるように
So that I can laugh until it hurts.
名前もない 僕らのセカイを
This nameless world of ours,
迷っていけるよ キミとだから
I can wander through, because I'm with you.
変わっていこう 願うように
Let's change, just as we wish,
今僕ら 期待の未体験を
Right now, let's experience the expected unknown.
飛び込んでいこう 僕らのセカイへ
Let's dive into our world,
正解の想いに出会えるかな
I wonder if we can find the right feelings?
歌っていたい 踊っていたい
I want to keep singing, keep dancing,
痛いくらい笑えるように
So that I can laugh until it hurts.
名前もない 僕らのセカイを
This nameless world of ours,
迷っていけるよ キミとだから
I can wander through, because I'm with you.
変わっていこう 願うように
Let's change, just as we wish,
今僕ら 期待の未体験を
Right now, let's experience the expected unknown.
キミの未来を僕が歌うよ 描いてもっと Yeah
I'll sing your future, let's draw it out even more, yeah!
泣いてもいいじゃん それも答えだ どうしたっていいよ
It's okay to cry, that's an answer too, however you want is fine.
想いは全部 零さぬように 抱き締めながら
Holding onto all these feelings so none of them spill,
キミと見たセカイへ
To the world I saw with you.
はーい！ありがとうございました！
Hi! Thank you very much!
ちょっと、ティッシュ…のどか、のどかティッシュくれ！
Wait, tissue... Nodoka, Nodoka, give me a tissue!
やばい。
Oh no.
あの、鼻水吹き出しちゃってさ、さっきね。
Um, I blew my nose just now, you know.
ちょっと待ってね、みんな。
Hold on a second, everyone.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
はい、というわけで、2曲目「セカイ」を聞いていただきました。どうですかみんな？
Right, so that was our second song, "Sekai". How was it, everyone?
ここが好きなんだよね、みんなどうかな？
I really like this part, I wonder how everyone feels?
ここね、お尻、お尻から見ててよ、お尻。
Right here, my butt—look at my butt!
どうよ？このプリプリのお尻！
How's that? This plump butt!
みんな見えたか みんなー！
Did everyone see that? Everyone!
はい、というわけで
Yes, so,
ここからは皆様、え、お待たせのゲストパートをいきたいと思います！
from here on, um, we'll be starting the long-awaited guest segment!
みんなね、サムネイルで、あのねどの先輩が来てくれるかもね、分かっていると思いますが
I'm sure you all know from the thumbnail which senior is coming, but...
一体どのような組み合わせで、どのように歌っているのか
exactly what kind of combination and how they'll sing—
え、謎はね、今日入りしたのでえ、それを解明しに行きたいと思います！
um, the mystery was solved today when we entered, so I'm going to go solve that mystery!
というわけで、みんなでね、あの頑張りますので要チェック！みんな目玉ひっぺがいて、あのこうやって画面に目玉を見せつけて
So everyone, we'll do our best, so check it out! Everyone, rip your eyeballs out and show them to the screen like this...
あのやってくだ、あ、やってください！あ、見てください！コメントしてください、見てますんで！
please do it! Ah, please watch! Please comment, I'm watching!
はい、というわけでいってみましょう！それではゲストパートスタートーー！ごごごごごごご
Yes, so let's check it out! Well then, the guest segment starts—! Go-go-go-go-go-go-go!
More More フッフー！ More More フッフー！ More More フッフー！ More More Jump!!
More More! More More! More More! More More Jump!!
限界超え 完全無欠スターを目指せ Jump!!
Beyond the limit, aim for the flawless star! Jump!!
元気シェア 負けない者の女神よ
Share the energy, O goddess of the undefeated!
消せぬ夢で結ばれた命
Lives bound by an unquenchable dream,
We are アイドル新鋭隊 (L・O・V・E)
We are the rookie idol corps! (L-O-V-E)
More More Jump!!
落ち込むなんて日常茶飯事
Getting down is an everyday occurrence,
けど速攻笑顔取り戻すわ
but I'll instantly take my smile back!
キューティー・スマイルみこち
Cutie Smile Mikochi!
一度きりのティーンの儚い花盛り
A fleeting blossom of a once-in-a-lifetime teen years,
下向いてちゃ人生は損
looking down means life's a loss—
フレッシュ・アイドル イェーイ！
Fresh Idol, yeah!
事務所の方針なんて無視
Ignoring the agency's policy,
ツンデレ・ガール あずき
Tsundere girl Azuki!
ビジネスライクで演じるのイヤ
I hate acting businesslike!
心に嘘つかず
Without lying to my heart,
spotlight 浴び step 踏めば
if I bathe in the spotlight and step,
駆け上がる道照らされるよ
the path I run up will be illuminated!
ウー・レッツゴー！
Ooh, let's go!
More More Jump!!
限界超え 完全無欠スターを目指せ Jump!!
Beyond the limit, aim for the flawless star! Jump!!
元気シェア 負けない者の女神よ
Share the energy, O goddess of the undefeated!
消せぬ夢で結ばれた命 We are アイドル新鋭隊 (L・O・V・E)
Lives bound by an unquenchable dream, We are the rookie idol corps! (L-O-V-E)
More More Jump!!
騒いだ者勝の世界でも
Even in a world where the loudest win,
ファイト・ファイト みこち
Fight, fight, Mikochi!
清楚可憐はアイドルの pride
Purity and grace are an idol's pride!
キューティー・スマイル すばる
Cutie Smile Subaru!
チヤホヤされて満足しちゃわないように
So I won't get satisfied just being pampered,
心広く志高く
keep your heart broad and your ambitions high!
ピュア・ピュア・ヒロイン イェーイ！
Pure, pure heroine, yeah!
仲悪いとか解散とか
Rumors of bad blood or disbanding,
ツンデレ・ガール あずき
Tsundere girl Azuki!
フェイク・ニュースに惑わされない
won't be swayed by fake news!
G・U・T・S ねねち
G-U-T-S Nenechi!
ハムより薄い女子の儚い友情だと
Thinking a girls' fragile friendship is thinner than ham—
そんな通説覆すパワー
that's the power to overturn such conventional wisdom!
ウー・レッツゴー！
Ooh, let's go!
More More Jump!!
涙を超え 千載一遇チャンス掴め Jump!!
Beyond tears, seize the once-in-a-lifetime chance! Jump!!
波飛び乗り 一世風靡起こそうよ
Ride the waves, let's create a sensation!
スターダムへのセトリ旅したら
If you make a setlist journey to superstardom,
あなたもアイドル新鋭隊 (L・O・V・E)
you too are part of the rookie idol corps! (L-O-V-E)
More More Jump!!
闇貫く レーザービームのように
Like a laser beam piercing through the darkness,
希望の光を放し続けて ウー・レッツゴー！
keep releasing the light of hope! Ooh, let's go!
More More Jump!!
限界超え 完全無欠スターを目指せ Jump!!
Beyond the limit, aim for the flawless star! Jump!!
元気シェア 負けない者の女神よ
Share the energy, O goddess of the undefeated!
消せぬ夢で結ばれた命 We are アイドル新鋭隊
Lives bound by an unquenchable dream, We are the rookie idol corps!
ミラクルへGO GO GO エスコート
Go, go, go to a miracle escort,
一緒に We are アイドル新鋭隊 (L・O・V・E)
together, We are the rookie idol corps! (L-O-V-E)
More More Jump!!
こころぴょんぴょん待ち？
Waiting with a fluttering heart?
考えるふりして もうちょっと 近づいちゃえ
Pretending to think, let's get a bit closer
簡単には教えない こんなに好きなことは
I won't tell you easily just how much I love this
内緒なの
It's a secret
ふわふわどきどき 内緒ですよ
Fluffy and thumping, it's a secret, you know
はじめがかんじん つーん だつーん だ
The start is crucial, tsun da tsun da!
ふわふわどきどき 内緒だって
Fluffy and thumping, it's a secret
いたずら笑顔で ぴょん ぴょん
With a mischievous smile, pyon pyon!
扉あけたとたん 見知らぬ世界へと
The moment I opened the door, into an unknown world
(そんなの ないよ) ありえない
(That can't be!) Impossible,
それが ありえるかも ミルク色の異次元
but maybe it's possible in a milk-colored dimension
(コーヒーカップ) 覗いたら
(A coffee cup) When I peeked inside,
私が 私を 見つめてました
I saw myself staring back at me
なんで？ なんで？
Why? Why?
ふたりいる？ (うそっ)
There are two of us? (No way!)
困りますね (きっと)
This is a pickle (Surely)
おんなじ趣味 (だから)
We share the same hobby (That's why)
誰を (見つめるの？ 君でしょ！)
Who are you (staring at? It's you!)
君だけ見てるよ
I'm only looking at you
(これは夢 カップの夢 飲みほして おしまい？)
(Is this a dream? A cup's dream, drink it down and it's over?)
いつもぴょんぴょん可能！ 楽しさ求めて
Always ready to pyon pyon! Seeking out the fun,
もうちょっと はじけちゃえ (ぴょんぴょん と)
let's let loose just a little more (pyon pyon!)
一緒に なら 素敵だあい！ 君に言わせたいから (言いなさい)
If we're together, it's wonderful! Wanting to make you say it (Say it!)
こころぴょんぴょん待ち？ 考えるふりして
Waiting with a fluttering heart? Pretending to think,
もうちょっと 近づいちゃえ (ぴょんぴょん と)
let's get a bit closer (pyon pyon!)
簡単には教えない こんなに好きなことは
I won't tell you easily, just how much I love this
(すきだってことは…… わわわっ！) 内緒なの
(That I love it... wawawa!) is a secret
ふわふわどきどき 内緒ですよ
Fluffy and thumping, it's a secret, you know
はじめがかんじん つーん だつーん だ
The start is crucial, tsun da tsun da!
ふわふわどきどき 内緒だって
Fluffy and thumping, it's a secret
いたずら笑顔で ぴょん ぴょん
With a mischievous smile, pyon pyon!
日常のなかにも 不思議の交差点
Even in everyday life, there's a mysterious intersection
(それならあるね) ありえるん
(That happens) It might be possible
ありえない角度に 切り分けたケーキが
A cake sliced at an impossible angle
(さすらいうさぎ) 呼んじゃったよ
(A wandering rabbit) called out to me
私も 私と 驚きました
I was surprised, saying "Me too!"
なんで？ なんで？
Why? Why?
しゃべるウサ？ (まじっ)
A talking rabbit? (Seriously?)
困りました (熱い)
I'm in a fix (It's hot!)
お茶を飲んで (うそだ)
Drink some tea (No way)
ついに (見つけたよ 君への)
Finally (I found it, my feelings for you)
君との運命
Destiny with you
(いいよね夢 恋の夢 初めてのときめき？)
(Isn't it nice? A dream of love, a first flutter?)
胸がらんらんうたう！
My heart sings happily!
スキップしながら はにかんで 誘ってよ (らんらん と)
Skipping along, acting shy, invite me out (ran ran!)
一緒に なら 無敵だあい！
Together, we're invincible!
本音隠せなくなる (本音だ)
I can't hide my true feelings anymore (True feelings!)
あしたらんらん希望？ 今すぐがいいな
Hoping for a cheerful tomorrow? I want it right now!
はにかんで 誘ってよ (らんらん と)
Acting shy, invite me out (ran ran!)
一瞬だけ耳もと
Just for a second, close to my ear
ほんとは好きなんだと (好きなんだ つまり…… なななっ!)
You whisper that you really love me (You love me, meaning... na-na-na!)
ささやく
Whispering it
(これは夢 カップの夢 飲みほして お願い？)
(Is this a dream? A cup's dream, drink it down, please?)
いつもぴょんぴょん可能！ 楽しさ求めて
Always ready to pyon pyon! Seeking out the fun,
もうちょっと はじけちゃえ (ぴょんぴょん と)
let's let loose just a little more (pyon pyon!)
一緒に なら 素敵だあい！ 君に言わせたいから (言いなさい)
If we're together, it's wonderful! Wanting to make you say it (Say it!)
こころぴょんぴょん待ち？ 考えるふりして
Waiting with a fluttering heart? Pretending to think,
もうちょっと 近づいちゃえ (ぴょんぴょん と)
let's get a bit closer (pyon pyon!)
簡単には教えない こんなに好きなことは
I won't tell you easily, just how much I love this
(すきだってことは…… わわわっ！) 内緒なの
(That I love it... wawawa!) is a secret
ふわふわどきどき 内緒ですよ
Fluffy and thumping, it's a secret, you know
はじめがかんじん つーん だつーん だ
The start is crucial, tsun da tsun da!
ふわふわどきどき 内緒だって
Fluffy and thumping, it's a secret
いたずら笑顔で ぴょん ぴょん
With a mischievous smile, pyon pyon!
いつもぴょんぴょん可能！ 楽しさ求めて
Always ready to pyon pyon! Seeking out the fun,
もうちょっと はじけちゃえ (ぴょんぴょん と)
let's let loose just a little more (pyon pyon!)
一緒に なら 素敵だあい！ 君に言わせたいから (言いなさい)
If we're together, it's wonderful! Wanting to make you say it (Say it!)
こころぴょんぴょん待ち？ 考えるふりして
Waiting with a fluttering heart? Pretending to think,
もうちょっと 近づいちゃえ (ぴょんぴょん と)
let's get a bit closer (pyon pyon!)
簡単には教えない こんなに好きなことは
I won't tell you easily, just how much I love this
内緒なの
It's a secret
ふわふわどきどき 内緒ですよ
Fluffy and thumping, it's a secret, you know
はじめがかんじん つーん だつーん だ
The start is crucial, tsun da tsun da!
ふわふわどきどき 内緒だって
Fluffy and thumping, it's a secret
いたずら笑顔で ぴょん ぴょん
With a mischievous smile, pyon pyon!
いつもぴょんぴょん可能！ 楽しさ求めて
Always ready to pyon pyon! Seeking out the fun,
もうちょっと はじけちゃえ (ぴょんぴょん と)
let's let loose just a little more (pyon pyon!)
一緒に なら 素敵だあい！ 君に言わせたいから (言いなさい)
If we're together, it's wonderful! Wanting to make you say it (Say it!)
いえーい！
Yay!
ねねちゃんの2周年を聞き届けていただきました！ありがとうございます！
Thank you all for witnessing Nene's 2nd anniversary! Thank you so much!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ふう… ちょっと疲れたわ。
Whew... I'm a bit tired.
そうね、めちゃめちゃ疲れたわ！
Right, we're super tired!
え、でも待って、練習の中でも一番間違えなかった…
Wait, out of all the rehearsals, that was the one where we made the least mistakes...
間違えちゃったわ！可愛かったから！
We messed up! But it was cute!
それも含めてミスも含めてかわいい！
Even with the mistakes, it was cute!
というわけで、今回はまつり先輩とあちゃもに来ていただきました！
So, for this time, we had Matsuri-senpai and Achamo come join us!
イェーイ！
Yay!
ありがとう、ありがとうございます！
Thank you, thank you so much!
ねぇたちさ、
Say, you guys...
え、実は？
Eh, actually?
ね、しゅうめい……
Ne, shuumei...
そうなんだよね、作っちゃったんだよね。
That's right, we made it.
じゃあ行きますよ！あいさつあるんで。
Alright, here we go! We have a greeting.
せーの！お疲れ様！
Ready, set! Good job!
ぴかーる、ぷー！
Pika-ru, poo!
あ、最近きとーおっしゃったもんね。
Ah, you were saying that recently, right?
むちゃくちゃ必死しゅうめいなんだす！
We're super desperately "shuumei"!
だからそういうこととかもね、詳しく話せる機会がどっかにあるといいね。
So it'd be great if there's an opportunity somewhere to talk about that in detail.
そうね！
Right!
いろんなことやりたいねん
There are so many things we want to do.
やりたい！やりたい！
We want to do them! We want to!
ということでね、この
So, moving forward,
今後も3人のね、動きに注目してもらえると嬉しいなあ！
we'd be so happy if you keep an eye out for what the three of us do!
ってなってなってなって…
Like, yeah, yeah, yeah...
なんて踊ろう、なんて踊ろう！
What should we dance to, what should we dance to!
MCってさ、次ライブがあったとしてもさ、呼んで呼んでいいの？呼んでいいの？
MC, even if there's another live, can we be invited? Can we?
え、どうしようかなって。呼んでよ！聞いてよ！
Like, what should we do? Invite us! Listen to us!
行くからぜひぜひ！
We'll go, absolutely!
はい、注目していてください！
Yes, please keep an eye out for us!
ダンスだけさ、どうだった？
And how about just the dance? How was it?
え、めちゃくちゃ可愛かった！これなんですよね！ハマっちゃう！
Ah, it was super cute! That's right! You just get hooked!
なんかまつりちゃんは、なんかダンスやってるイメージがあったんだけど
It felt like Matsuri-chan already had an image of doing dances, but...
はーちゃまを誘う時に、なんかはーちゃまま「やるっちゃーー！」って言うから
when inviting Haachama, Haachama went, "Let's do it~~!"
なになに、はーちゃまとして、もうめちゃくちゃ…
What, what, as Haachama, she was super...
言ってたから、え、じゃあ、ほうちょうも来てくれる？
saying that, so, "Ah, then will Houchou come too?"
来てくれました！
She came!
そう、2人返事してくれてありがとう！
That's right, thank you both for replying!
嬉しい！
Yay!
え、どこが難しかった？
Um, where was difficult?
えー、でもやっぱり最後の角変みたいな、急にさ！ね！これが急に、これが突然来るからさ！
Um, but after all, that sudden horn-change part, it suddenly comes out of nowhere! Right?
そうそうそうそう。あと間際のさ、途中、これの
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Also right before that, midway, this part—
ええと、気合い入れた！ぶちかまぶちかました、びっくりした！
Um, I got pumped! We went all out, I was surprised!
そこも観てほしいです！
We want you to watch that part too!
はい、ということで、疲れちゃいますか？
Okay, so, are you getting tired?
まだあるでしょ？頑張って、頑張ってね！まだまだあるので、この後もお楽しみください！
There's still more to come, so please look forward to the rest!
はーい！というわけで、締めの一言までうちら考えたんだよね！じゃあやろう！
Yay! So, we even thought up a closing remark! Let's do it!
えっとなんと、せーの、レッツ・ピーカーブー！
Um, ready, set, let's peekaboo!
誰が袖に咲く幻花
Who is the phantom flower that blooms on the sleeve?
ただ そこに藍を落とした
I just dropped my indigo dye over there.
派手に色を溶かす夜に
On a night when the colors dissolve gaudily,
銀朱の月を添えて
with the silver-vermilion moon.
転がるように風を切って
Cutting through the wind as if rolling,
躓くことに強くなった
I grew stronger with every stumble.
光も痛みも怒りも全部 抱きしめて
Embracing all the light, pain, and anger—
選ばれなければ 選べばいい
if I am not chosen, I'll just choose myself.
声よ 轟け 夜のその向こうへ
Let my voice roar out beyond the night,
涙で にじんでた
blurring with tears,
あんなに 遠くの 景色まで 響きわたれ
echoing all the way to that distant scenery.
何を 奏でて？ 誰に 届けたくて？
What am I playing? Who do I want to reach?
ふたしかな ままでいい
It's okay to remain uncertain.
どんなに 暗い 感情も
No matter how dark the emotions,
どんなに 長い 葛藤も
no matter how long the struggle,
歌と散れ 残響
scatter with the song, reverberation!
ただ ひとり舞う 千夜
Dancing alone through a thousand nights,
たがえない 帯を結ばれば
if I tie my unwavering sash,
派らかな色も 満たすように
as if filling even the gaudy colors—
朱紅の過去こそ あわれえ
the crimson past itself is bewitching.
この先 どんな つらい 時も
No matter how painful times get ahead,
口さき よりも 胸を張って
I'll puff out my chest rather than just talk.
抱いた 夢の 灯りを 全部 辿るだけ
I'll just follow every light of the dreams I held.
逃げ出す ため ここまで 来たんじゃないだろ？
I didn't come all this way just to run away, right?
選ばれなければ 選べばいい
If I'm not chosen, I'll just choose!
If not chosen, I'll just choose!
選ばれなければ 選べばいい
声を からして 燃える 花の ように
Like a flower burning with a hoarse voice,
闇間を 照らしたら
once it illuminates the darkness,
曖昧 過ぎる 正解も 譜面にして
turn even overly vague correct answers into a musical score.
夜を 数えて 朝を描く ような 鮮やかな 音を鳴らす
Playing a vivid sound like counting nights and painting mornings,
どんなに 深い 後悔も
no matter how deep the regret,
どんなに 高い 限界も
no matter how high the limit,
かき消して 残響
scratch it all out, reverberation!
あー！
Aah!
やり切った！
We did it!
やり切ったね！
We really did it!
一番完成度高かった気がする
I feel like this was our highest completion yet!
ダッシュ・スピードで...
With dash speed...
イェーイ！
Yay!
3人で踊るのは なんと半年ぶりということでなんだよね
Dancing together as three is actually our first time in half a year, right?
生のね、動けちゃったね。
Yeah, we totally pulled it off live!
いや、今回もちょっとかっこいい感じにしてみたんだけど
Well, we tried to go for a cool vibe this time,
どうだったでしょうか？
how did it go?
いや、めちゃくちゃ疲れたよね！
Man, we were so exhausted!
緊張感めちゃ半端なかったわ！
The tension was unreal!
なんていくも繰り返しましたけれども
We repeated it so many times...
本当に汗だくだくな
We were drenched in sweat,
順番にミスって行きました
and messed up the order one by one!
でもやり切った！イェーイ！
But we pulled it off! Yay!
ダッシュ・スピード！
Dash speed!
とりあえずおめでとう！ありがとう！
Anyway, congratulations! Thank you!
おめでと！
Congratulations!
2周年早い！ありがとう！
2nd anniversary is so fast! Thank you!
3年目だよね。3年目もよろしくお願いします！
It's our 3rd year. Looking forward to year 3 as well!
そして、このダッシュ・スピード自体もね
And this Dash Speed itself...
あと2ヶ月で1周年らしいです。
Is apparently 1 year old in 2 months.
そうだよ！
That's right!
クリスマス、クリスマス...の、あのクリスマスの...覚えたでしょ？
Christmas, Christmas... do you remember the Christmas one?
届けて切なさ...あ、間違えた！
Delivering sorrow... Ah, I messed up!
あ、間違えた！あせった！あせった！
Ah, I messed up! I panicked!
あれもめちゃ頑張ったし
We worked so hard on that one too!
生放送だったから なんか謎の緊張感があってね
Since it was a live broadcast, there was this mysterious tension!
今回成功するまでやりました！
We kept going until we succeeded this time!
また生放送でもやりたいよね！企画するから来てよね。
I'd love to do it on a live broadcast again! We'll plan it, so come on!
練習いっぱい付き合ってくれるから大好き！
They accompany us through tons of practice, so I love them!
今日はね、なんかちょっとおそろいの衣装っぽい感じで
Today, we kind of have matching outfits sort of vibe.
みんなパーカー、ジャケット着てるじゃん。ジャケット、スウェットもジャケット。
Yeah, everyone's wearing hoodies, jackets... jackets, sweatshirts are jackets too.
スクショ撮ってもらうよ。
Let's have them take a screenshot.
スクショ！イェーイ！
Screenshot! Yay!
おい、とわ乗れ！乗ってもらいよ！イェーイ！
Hey Towa, ride along! Get on! Yay!
次はブリッコ、ブリッコ、ブリッコ、ブリッコ！
Next is burikko, burikko!
次はキュンのポーズよ！キュンのポーズ！
Next is the heart pose! Heart pose!
あれ？はい、キュンのポーズ！キュンして！
Huh? Yes, heart pose! Make a heart!
みんな愛してるわ。はい、とわ先輩？キュン！
Everyone, I love you. Yes, Towa-senpai? Heart!
みんなねねの愛してるが欲しいんでしょ？
Everyone wants Nene's "I love you," right?
ねねの愛してるが欲しいよね、今日だってねねが主役なんだから。
You want Nene's "I love you," right? Today Nene is the star after all.
ねねの愛してる、安っ！誰にも聞けないかな？
Nene's "I love you" is cheap! Can nobody hear it?
聞けない、聞けない！
Can't hear it, can't hear it!
早く安定してほしいもう！
I just want it to stabilize already!
はい、ということで、最後の締めくくりの言葉は？
Right, so... what are the final closing words?
行くよ！せーの、つながるダッシュ・スピード！
Here we go! Ready, set, Connected Dash Speed!
いいでしょ？
Isn't that good?
遠くで
Far away,
far away,
揺れてる稲穂の海
a swaying sea of rice grains.
帆上げ
Raise the sails,
帆上げ 帆上げ
raise the sails, raise the sails,
目指した想い出へと
heading toward the memories we aimed for.
僕らは今日までの 悲しいこと全部
Do we remember all the sad things up until today,
覚えてるか
do we remember them,
忘れたか
or have we forgotten?
小さな手にも
Even in our small hands,
いつからか僕ら
since when have we
追い越してく強さ
gained the strength to surpass it?
熟れた葡萄の下 泣いてた日から
From the days we cried beneath the ripe grapes,
歩いた
we walked on.
小さな手でも 離れても
Even with small hands, even when apart,
僕らはこの道行くんだ
we will walk down this road.
いつか来る日は 一番の想い出をしまって
Storing away our dearest memories for the day to come...
季節は移り
The seasons change,
もう冷たい風が
and a cold wind now blows,
包んで眠れ あの春の歌の中で
sleep embraced in the song of that spring.
小さな手にも いつからか僕ら
Even in our small hands, since when have we
追い越してく強さ
gained the strength to surpass it?
濡れた頬には どれだけの笑顔が映った
How many smiles were reflected on our wet cheeks?
小さな手でも 離れても
Even with small hands, even when apart,
僕らはこの道行くんだ
we will walk down this road.
そして来る日は 僕らも想い出をしまった
And on the day to come, we too stored away our memories.
小さな手でも いつかの日が
Even with small hands, the day will come
僕ら追い越してゆくんだ
when we surpass it and move on.
やがて来る日は 新しい季節を開いた
The day that eventually came opened a new season.
はーい、というわけで、えー、「小さな手のひら」、
Alright, so that was "Chiisana Tenohira",
そしてゲストパートを見ていただきました！ありがとうございましたー！
and the guest part! Thank you very much!
「小さな手のひら」ね、リクエスト多かったんですよね。
"Chiisana Tenohira" had a lot of requests.
どうでしたか？お楽しみいただけましたでしょうか？
How was it? Did you enjoy it?
そしてゲストパートはいかがでしたか？あの、みんな来てくれてありがとうございました。
And how was the guest part? Thanks for coming, everyone!
みんな、みんなかわいくて、よかったです！
Everyone was so cute, it was great!
またあそんでくださーい！
Please play with us again!
あ、で、せっかくだからみんな気づいちゃった？
Oh, and did everyone notice?
これ、これ、このヘッドセット作ってもらいました！
Look, they made me this headset!
ねねのオリジナルのね、だけのヘッドセット。かわいい！
Nene's very own original headset. Cute!
この遠くから見たときにもこの圧倒的存在感。
Even from far away, it has this overwhelming presence.
かわいい！素晴らしい！素晴らしい！
Cute! Wonderful! Wonderful!
あ、みんなトレンド１位入れてくれてありがとう！
And thank you for getting us to #1 on trends!
ちょっとサービスしてあげようか？今日ね、スカートの調子がいいから…ほら！ほら！
Shall I give you some fanservice? My skirt is doing great so... Look!
激、激々サービス。
Super extreme fanservice.
あ、ちょっとお水飲みつつ。
Phew, drinking some water.
え？いーじゃん。ほら、うら、うら、うら、うら！
Eh? That's fine, right? Look, back, back, back!
じゃあ次の曲いっちゃおうかな。次の曲もリクエストがあった曲なので…
Well then, shall we move on to the next song?
ふぅ…
Whew...
やばい…
Oh no...
はぁ…
Hah...
ふぅ、よし。やっと整えどうして…
Whew, okay. Finally got myself together...
よし、行きましょう！ってことで、
Alright, let's go! With that said,
それでは次の曲聞いてください。
please listen to the next song.
バニラソルト！
Vanilla Salt!
バニラソルトで
With vanilla salt
Burning Love
アマイだけなら
If it's just sweet
ソルトかけましょう
Then let's salt it
誰よりももっともっと私を
More than anyone else, I want you
知って欲しいからさらけだしたい
to know me, so I want to bare myself
でも出来ないの経験Nothing
But I can't do it, I've got no experience
モドカシすぎる
It's too frustrating
弱みみせようとすればするほど
The more I try to show my weakness
ムダに強がりすべてがウラハラ
The more I act tough in vain, everything goes the other way
本当は私泣き虫なんだ
I'm actually a crybaby
黙ってたけど
Though I've been mum about that
でも、アマイだけの愛はちょっと
But a love that's just sweet is slightly...
私が求めているモノとは違う
Different from what I'm seeking
シロと言われたら
If I'm told it's white
クロだって言っちゃう
I'd say it's black
素直になれない
I can't be honest
アマノジャク
I'm an obstinate person
スキと言われたら
If I'm told "I love you"
ダイキライだって
I'd say "I hate you"
嬉しいのにナニ言ってんだろう?
I'm happy, but what am I saying?
アマイバニラにソルトかけるように…
Like putting salt into sweet vanilla...
一途にスキになってしまったら
When I fall head over heels in love
24時間7日間ずっと
For all the time, 24/7
あなたのことをひたすらI think
I think about you continuously
かなり極端
It's rather extreme
まさかここまであなたにハマると
Can it be, that no one ever thought
誰も予想なんてしてなかった
that I'd be this obsessed with you?
天気予報じゃ当たらないんだ
Weather forecasts can't tell
恋の行方は
The whereabouts of love
2人で一緒にいる時間に刻まれた想い出はタカラモノなんだ
My memories engraved into the periods of time when we're together are treasures
右と言われたら
If I'm told it's right
左に曲がっちゃう
I'd turn left
素直になれない
I can't be honest
アマノジャク
I'm an obstinate person
スキと言われたら
If I'm told "I love you"
ダイキライだって
I'd say "I hate you"
嬉しいのにナニ言ってんだろう?
I'm happy, but what am I saying?
Burning Love
アマイだけのバニラより
Rather than the vanilla that's just sweet
ちょっと塩した方が
The slightly salted kind
甘みも増してゆくしね
Makes it sweeter
飽きがこない…
I can't get tired of it...
アマイだけの愛もそう
It's the same with the love that's just sweet
ちょっと塩した方が
The slightly salted kind
2人の距離も縮まり
Shrinks the distance between us
きっと
And I'm sure
今日より素敵な未来が待ってるの
That a future more wonderful than today is waiting
シロと言われたら
If I'm told it's white
クロだって言っちゃう
I'd say it's black
素直になれない
I can't be honest
アマノジャク
I'm an obstinate person
スキと言われたら
If I'm told "I love you"
ダイキライだって
I'd say "I hate you"
嬉しいのにナニ言ってんだろう?
I'm happy, but what am I saying?
アマイだけでも
If it's just sweet
ソルトかけましょう
Then let's salt it
バニラソルトで
With vanilla salt
Burning Love
アマイだけのバニラより
Rather than the vanilla that's just sweet
ちょっと塩した方が
The slightly salted kind
甘みも増してゆくしね
Makes it sweeter
飽きがこない…
I can't get tired of it...
アマイだけの愛もそう
It's the same with the love that's just sweet
ちょっと塩した方が
The slightly salted kind
2人の距離も縮まり
Shrinks the distance between us
きっと
And I'm sure
今日より素敵な未来が待ってるの
That a future more wonderful than today is waiting
シロと言われたら
If I'm told it's white
クロだって言っちゃう
I'd say it's black
素直になれない
I can't be honest
アマノジャク
I'm an obstinate person
スキと言われたら
If I'm told "I love you"
ダイキライだって
I'd say "I hate you"
嬉しいのにナニ言ってんだろう?
I'm happy, but what am I saying?
アマイだけでも
If it's just sweet
ソルトかけましょう
Then let's salt it
アマイ
Sweet
バニラにソルトかけるように…
Like putting salt into sweet vanilla...
バニラソルトで
With vanilla salt
With vanilla salt,
バニラソルトで
with vanilla salt,
はーい！というわけで、トロンダラからバニラソルトお届けできましたー！
Hii! So, we were able to deliver Vanilla Salt from Torondara!
ちょっと待ってね。
Hold on a second.
どうだった？
How was it?
どうですか？あっ、そうそう。
How did you like it? Ah, right, right.
あ、これはみんな、心の綺麗な人にしか見えないお水です。
Ah, this is water that can only be seen by people with pure hearts.
マネレンには見えてるけど、みんなには見えんだろーなー！
Mane-ren can see it, but you guys probably can't see it!
はー、鼻水……
Haah, a runny nose...
今大丈夫だよ。なんかちょっと鼻声だよね。
I'm okay now. My voice sounds a bit nasal, huh.
鼻、鼻詰まってないんだけどね、なんかそろそろ手術が生えてくるから本当厄介だわ。
My nose isn't blocked, but stitches are about to grow in, which is really a pain.
でも今は大丈夫です。
But I'm fine right now.
はい！ えー、さて、えーサムネにもさ、みんな、いっぱい告知あり！みたい感じ書いてあって、あったでしょ？
Right! Um, well, in the thumbnail too, everyone, it said something like "Lots of announcements!", right?
そのうちの1つ目、1つ目！ここで発表しまーす！
The first one of those, the first one! I'll announce it right here!
えー、重大発表！その、わあー！
Um, major announcement! That... Wow!
えー、それは、ねえねえの、新しいオリジナルソングが……！
Um, that is, Nene-ne's new original song...
オリジナルソングが……！
new original song...
でます！じゃじゃーん！
is coming out! Ta-da!
こちら！うわあ、でも、なんか、ジャケット可愛いでしょう？
Here! Wow, but look, isn't the jacket cute?
えっ、いい感じ、エモい顔しちゃって。
Eh, looks nice, making an emotional face.
これみんな読めますか？これね、あの、ちょっとかっこいい英語で書いてあるから、ちょっとねねが読んであげます。
Can everyone read this? This, you know, is written in some cool English, so Nene will read it for you.
Ring-A-Linger、Ring-A-Lingerです。
It's Ring-A-Linger, Ring-A-Linger.
いいでしょ？響きがいいでしょ？覚えた？みんな。
Isn't it nice? Doesn't it sound good? Did you memorize it, everyone?
どんな曲だと思う？みんな、聴きたいでしょ？
What kind of song do you think it is? Everyone wants to hear it, right?
うーん、こんなね、イケイケハレハレも……
Hmm, such high-energy and bright...
ひと、ひとたまりお水を飲めば……
If you drink a sip of water...
えっ、どんな曲？どっち系だと思う？しっとり系だと思う？元気系だと思う？
Eh, what kind of song is it? Which type do you think? Do you think it's a mellow type? Do you think it's an energetic type?
えっとね、こちら、今回もヒゲドライバーさんが作ってくれたんですけど、今回はちょっとね、今までの一番ねの雰囲気とはちょっと違う感じなんじゃないかなって思ってるんですけど……
Um, this time too, Hige Driver-san made it, but I think this time it's a bit different vibe from until now...
ちょっと聴いてもらおうかな？じゃあみんなに。ちょっとね、まずいよ、これが一番ね、ね、あの……まずいから。
Shall I have you listen to it? Well, to everyone. You know, it's bad, this is the most... you know... because it's bad.
緊張しちゃうんだよね、難しいんだよ！これめっちゃ難しいから、うーん、ちょっと待って、間違いちょっと、でもみんなね、わかんないから、初めてだから！
I get nervous, it's difficult! This is super difficult, um, wait, a mistake, well, but everyone doesn't know, it's the first time!
いや、言ってみますかじゃあ！ということで、それでは聴いてください。
Well, shall I give it a try then! With that said, please listen.
ももすずねね 新しいオリジナルソング『Ring-A-Linger』
Momosuzu Nene's new original song "Ring-A-Linger"
空、空 いつの間にか暗くなってさ
Sky, sky, before I knew it, it got dark,
音、音 寂しくないよう包んで
Sound, sound, wrap me up so I won't feel lonely,
時間、時間 黙ってても去っていくなら
Time, time, if it passes even if I stay silent,
夢、夢 追いかけるよう踏み出すステップ
Dream, dream, take a step forward to chase it,
悩みもすぐに書き消すくらい響いていく音
A sound echoing loud enough to instantly erase worries.
響いていく音
The resonating sound...
Ring-A-Linger
Ring-A-Linger カラダは
Ring-A-Linger, my body
透明なビート感じて
feels the transparent beat,
自然と動き出している
and naturally starts moving.
ほらほらほら
Look, look, look!
Ring-A-Linger
Ring-A-Linger ココロは
Ring-A-Linger, my heart
キミのココロと共鳴して
resonates with your heart,
喜びの鈴が鳴る
and the bell of joy rings.
ほらほらほら
Look, look, look!
踊ろ 踊ろ 踊ろう
Dance, dance, let's dance!
花、花
Flowers, flowers,
花、花 真っ直ぐ生きていたいけど
I want to live straight, but...
風、風
Winds, winds,
風、風 背伸びするほど強くて
so strong it makes me stretch,
未来、未来 上手く予想できないけど
I can't predict the future well, but...
自問自答するように繰り返すムーブ
repeating moves like asking myself questions—
同じリズムで、キミとわたし
in the same rhythm, you and I,
鼓動重ねたら、さあ
when our heartbeats overlap, come on!
Ring-A-Linger 大丈夫
Ring-A-Linger, it's alright,
今はもう迷うことはない
there's no hesitation anymore,
メロディーの示すほうへ
towards where the melody points.
ほらほらほら
Look, look, look!
Ring-A-Linger 涙も
Ring-A-Linger, even tears
汗も生きている証拠なら
and sweat are proof of life—
ここにいるって声上げよう
let's raise our voices that we're here!
ほらほらほら 踊ろ
Look, look, look, dance!
真っ暗な夜が来て 見えなくなってしまう前に
Before the pitch-dark night comes and hides everything,
もっと もっと もっと もっと
more, more, more, more!
Ring-A-Linger
Ring-A-Linger カラダは
Ring-A-Linger, my body
透明なビート感じて
feels the transparent beat,
自然と動き出している
and naturally starts moving.
ほらほらほら
Look, look, look!
Ring-A-Linger
Ring-A-Linger ココロは
Ring-A-Linger, my heart
キミのココロと共鳴して
resonates with your heart,
喜びの鈴が鳴る
and the bell of joy rings.
ほらほらほら
Look, look, look!
踊ろ 踊ろ 踊ろう
Dance, dance, let's dance!
はーい、というわけでいかがだったでしょうか！新しい曲「Ring-A-Linger」でしたー！
Hiii, so how was that?! That was my new song, "Ring-A-Linger"!
はぁー、はぁーめちゃくちゃ、めちゃくちゃ…こく…こく…！
Haah, haah... I'm so out of breath...!
ダンスのカロリーが高くて！
The dance is so high-energy!
そして、え、この、あ、ちょっと待って。この「Ring-A-Linger」なんですけれども！
And, um, regarding this "Ring-A-Linger"...
このあと、22時15分からなんとフル尺の3Dの完全版のMVがプレミア公開されます！いぇーい！
Tonight at 22:15, the full 3D music video will premiere! Yay!
ちょっとね、今ね、ねぇ、息も乱れてあのボロボロだった音源をMVで綺麗に綺麗な綺麗なになってますので！
My breath is ragged and live vocals were rough, but the MV is super polished!
でもお楽しみに！そしてこの楽曲は、え、このあとの0時からですネ、23時の…に成り立ての時間から、各音楽サイトで配信されますので！
Please look forward to it! And this song will be available on all music sites at midnight...
皆様よかったら、あの、これからのね、あの、活動のためにもたくさん聴いてくれると嬉しいです！さらにさらに、重大発表の、っつ…！なんと「Ring-A-Linger」のタイアップが決定しました！
I'd be so happy if you listen to it a lot! And "Ring-A-Linger" has a tie-up!
こちら、あ、はい、なんと読売テレビさんそして日本テレビさんで放送中の「川島・山内のマンガ沼」...
It's the ending theme for Yomiuri TV and Nippon TV's "Kawashima & Yamauchi's Manga Swamp"!
「川島・山内のマンガ沼」という番組のエンディングテーマになりました！イエーイ！
It's been chosen as the ending theme for Kawashima & Yamauchi's Manga Numa! Yay!
ほーほほほほほー！
Woohoo!
放送日とか時間帯の詳細は、このあとホロライブミュージックのTwitterから詳細が出ますので、そちらを見てください。
Details on broadcast dates and times will be posted on HoloLive Music's Twitter afterward, so please check that out.
見てねー！
Check it out!
わー、エンディングでねねの歌聴けるのすごい！イエーイ、わー！
Wow, it's amazing to hear Nene's song in the ending! Yay, wow!
というわけで、2周年ライブ、ここまでお楽しみいただけましたでしょうか？みんなツイートいっぱいいっぱい撮ってね！
So, did you enjoy the 2nd anniversary live so far? Everyone, make sure to post lots of tweets!
このあとアンコールが絶対にあるので、皆さん、あの、よければ、ここでおわっちゃうかもしれないんですけど、絶対にあるので、絶対ここまで告知してないことがあるので、皆さん、あのこのあとね、アンコールコールして、お見送りに待っててください。いいですか？
There's definitely an encore coming up, so everyone, if you'd like... it might seem like it's ending here, but there's definitely more, and some announcements we haven't made yet. So please do an encore call after this and wait to see us off, okay?
できる？みんな、アンコールだよ。よし、じゃあみんな、ということで
Can you do it? Everyone, it's encore time! Alright, everyone, with that...
耳に耳に来てくれてありがとうね！
Thank you so much for coming to see me!
あー、アンコール！
Ah, encore!
あ、ちょっとシームして、あ、終わっちゃった！今聞いたばっか！
Ah, wait a second... Ah, it ended! I just heard that!
アンコールあんどアルコール、あ、いっしょ、いっしょ、いっしょ、いっしょわー！
Encore and alcohol! Ah, together, together, together, yay!
みんな、アンコールありがとう！絶対に、あるアンコールありがとう！このあとね、ラスト一曲やらせていただきたいと思うのですが
Everyone, thank you for the encore! Thank you for the definite encore! After this, I'd like to perform one last song, but...
その前にねねから、お知らせがあるよ、告知があるよ！はい！こちら！
Before that, Nene has an announcement for you! Yes! Right here!
ももすずねね2周年記念のグッズが出ます！イエーイ！待ってた？イエーイ、わー！えー、わあ、かわいいね！え、ちょっとみんな、よく見て！
Momosuzu Nene's 2nd anniversary merchandise is coming out! Yay! Were you waiting for it? Yay, wow! Eh, wow, so cute! Hey everyone, take a close look!
記念何、何のグッズがあるだって？みんな、よく見て、よく見て！こちら！
What kind of merchandise is there for the anniversary, you ask? Everyone, look closely! Right here!
まずはねねのファーストEP「ねねのね！」CDね！CD「ねねのね」の、発売、イエーイ！
First is Nene's 1st EP "Nenene no Ne!" CD! The CD release of "Nenene no Ne", yay!
猫もよろこんでる！わー、やばい！
The cat is happy too! Wow, this is crazy!
みんな、ねね、今までのねねの曲プラス4曲目はなんと、CDを交代して、交代した人が一番最初に聴けるビッグビッグな曲！なんとねねが作詞をして気持ちを込めたんだとか！なんだとか！これはやばい見逃すべき聞いてください！
Everyone, Nene—plus all of Nene's previous songs, the 4th song is a big, big track that the person who switches CDs can listen to first! Apparently Nene wrote the lyrics and poured her feelings into it! Or so they say! This is crazy, you shouldn't miss it, please listen!
そして今回のリンガリンガ入って全5曲、ヒゲドライバーさんでいっぱいの、ねねのねファーストEP、発売ー！そしてこちら！
And with "Ring-A-Linger", a total of 5 tracks filled with Hige Driver, Nene's 1st EP is on sale! And next, this!
B2タペストリー！はい、これね、8月に発表する予定だったんで思いっきり水着になっちゃいました。ちょっと今寒いかもしれないけど、でもね、そんな寒さを吹き飛ばすくらい、あの、あまりにもねねがえっちすぎてみんなの目が取れてしまいます。
B2 Tapestry! Yes, this was supposed to be announced in August, so she's in full swimsuit mode. It might be a little cold right now, but even so, to blow away that cold, well... Nene is so lewd that everyone's eyes will pop right out!
こうちょっとね、みんなの予想もしない大人っぽい水着を着て、お写真撮ってもらいました。こんな感じでね。あまりにもえっちすぎてみんなが大興奮してしまう、素晴らしいとっても可愛く仕上げていただきました！
I wore a mature swimsuit that everyone wouldn't expect and had photos taken. Something like this. It's so lewd that everyone will get super excited—they finished it so wonderfully and cutely!
そして次！履けるタイプのごぼうねっこスリッパ！これね、めっっちゃかわいいから！すごい、でかくて、なんかもうギシギシギシドン！ドン！ドン！ドン！ドン！ドン！って感じで、履けるタイプの履きつぶすタイプのねっこでございます。生まれた人、自分の自分のことを踏んでください。かわいいね！そして次！
And next! Wearable burdock root slippers! These are super cute! They're huge and make a stomping, squeaking sound like *don don don*, so they're wearable, stompable roots. If you were born... well, step on your own self! So cute! And next!
これ被れるタイプのねっこです。あ、身に着けるものが好きすぎるねね！
This is a wearable hat-style root! Ah, Nene just loves things you can wear!
これね、あのテーマパークみたいにね、
This is like a theme park thing,
頭にぎゃんっ!ってピシッて止めるタイプの…
you slap it gyan! and snap it on your head...
かぶりねこすねこです！
It's a wearable Neko-sune-ko!
これね、大きかったからね、あの男の人でもいけると思います。
Since it's big, I think even guys can wear it.
これからね、寒いので、頭ちょっと涼しいなって思う人はどうですか？
Since it's getting cold now, what about those whose heads feel a bit chilly?
いいでしょう？これめっちゃ可愛かった！
Isn't it nice? This is super cute!
大きい、大きい結構これくらいある。あ、ちょっと持ったかもこれくらい。
It's big, quite big, about this much. Ah, I might be holding it a bit smaller.
え、めっちゃ可愛いこれ！これは、あの被り尽くすタイプのねこちゃんなんで、あの被りたい方被ってください！
Eh, super cute! This is a full-coverage Neko-chan, so those who want to wear it, please do!
いいよ、これで会社行っていいよ！学校も、おうちも、なんかね、あの次からのね、ねの放送見る時はこれ被ってきてください。
It's fine, you can go to work in this! School too, home too... um, next time you watch Nene's broadcast, please wear this.
そして、えーこれフルセットの内容になるんですけど、今回ボイスがですね、皆さんからリクエストあったシステムボイスになってます！
And, uh, this will be the contents of the full set, but this time the voice is a system voice requested by everyone!
みんなのねPCのね、あの操作音をね、ビシッと、あの、ステキにしてやりますので、こちらのフ…あ、じゃない、システムボイスで楽しんでください！
I will make everyone's PC operation sounds crisp and wonderful, so please enjoy with the system voice!
そして、えーフルセット購入特典、torino描き下ろしチェキ風ブロマイドカード！ねのね、あっちの水着の、あの、お写真チェキになります！
And full set purchase bonus: torino's newly illustrated cheki-style bromide card! It'll be Nene's swimsuit photo cheki!
そして、ご…ごほうびじゃなくて、あ、ちょっとネタバレになっちゃった！え、特典ボイスが記念につきますので、よかったらそちらも聞いてください！
And, um, a commemorative bonus voice comes with it, so please listen to that too if you like!
はい、というわけで、たくさん告知しました！よし。ちょっと待って、時間やばい、時間やばい！ごめんなさい！
Right, well, I made a lot of announcements! Okay. Wait a second, time's up, time's up! I'm sorry!
あ、時間ごめんなさいなんですけど、最後に1曲だけやらせてください。この後、お水、お水飲むからね。
Ah, sorry about the time, but please let me do just one last song. After this, I'll drink some water.
え？あ、まだ水飲んでないんだから。おい！
Eh? Ah, I haven't even drank water yet. Hey!
え？特報？なんだ？あ、ちょっと待って、最初によく見えなかったんだけど。
Eh? Special report? What is it? Ah, wait a minute, I couldn't see it well at first.
え！？みんな！え！？うそ！ま、ま、まじか！おまっすねね！ファーストEP「ねねのね！」発売記念！
Eh?! Everyone?! Eh?! No way! Se-se-seriously! Omatsuri Nene! 1st EP "Nene no Ne!" release commemoration!
ファーミーティング、ねねかいぎを開催することになりました！やったー！イエーイ！やったー！
Fan meeting, Nene-kaigi will be held! Yay! Yay! Yay!
えー！わあ！日程がなんと2023年1月14日！来年！来年のお正月過ぎた当たりの土曜日！場所は、東京都内某所！
The date is January 14, 2023! Saturday right after New Year's! The place is somewhere in Tokyo!
トークショーと、サイン会と、ミニライブも予定しています！だって！え、やった！有観客じゃん！有客じゃん！やった！1月14日皆さん開けておいてください！お願いします！
A talk show, signing event, and mini-live are planned! Everyone please keep January 14 open! Please!
まだ間に合うやろ、休み取ってくれ！応募方法はグッズの販売ページに書いてあるので、皆さんこちら要チェックでございます！
You still have time, take days off! Application methods are on the merchandise sales page, so everyone please check this out!
このネコもっともこもこみんな。それじゃ最後の曲聞いてください！
This cat is extra fluffy, everyone. Well then, please listen to the final song!
だから もっと 近づきたいから
Because I want to get closer,
もっと 声きかせて
let me hear your voice more.
その手 掴んだら はなさないから
Once I grab your hand, I won't let go.
(いっせーのーで もっともっと ジャンプ！はい！)
(On the count of three, jump higher and higher! Hey!)
まだ最初は 消えちゃいそうな想いから
From feelings that seemed like they'd fade at first,
気づいたら 動き出したストーリー
before I knew it, a story started moving.
ひとりじゃ 届きそうもない場所
To a place that seemed impossible to reach alone,
夢じゃない あなたがいるから
you are here, so it's no dream.
(ホップ ステップ ジャンプ はい！)
(Hop, step, jump, hey!)
未来でも 世界でも 未知に満ち足りなくなっても
In the future, in the world, even if the unknown isn't enough,
そんなの飛び越えて！
we'll leap right over that!
だから もっと 近づきたいから
Because I want to get closer,
だからもっと近づきたいからもっと声きかせて
I want to get closer, so let me hear your voice more!
その手掴んだらはなさないから
Once I grab that hand, I won't let go.
いっせーので
One, two, three, go!
もっともっとジャンプ！
Jump more and more!
ハイ！
Hey!
まだ最初は消えちゃいそうな想いから
Even feelings that seemed like they might vanish at first...
(一歩ずつ)気づいたら動き出したストーリー
Before I knew it, the story started moving.
(いちにーさんはいっ！)
(One, two, three, go!)
ひとりじゃ届きそうもない場所
In a place where it felt like it wouldn't reach alone...
(今はいもう)夢じゃないあなたがいるから
Now you are here, and it's no longer just a dream.
(ホップ　ステップ　ジャンプ　はいっ！)
(Hop, step, jump, go!)
未来でも世界でも
Even in the future, even in the world,
未知に満ち足りなくなっても
even if we run out of things to discover,
そんなの飛び越えて！
we'll fly right past all of that!
だからもっと(もっと)近づきたいから
That's why I want to get closer,
もっと(もっと)声きかせて
so let me hear your voice more!
今鳴ったハートのビートが
The heartbeat that just started ringing...
とめられない！とめたくない！
Can't be stopped! I don't want to stop it!
(ない　ない！)
(No, no!)
もっと(もっと)アイをしたいから
I want to share more love,
もっと(もっと)愛をちょーだい
so give me more love!
その手掴んだらはなさないから
Once I grab that hand, I won't let go!
(モア＆モア！)声をもっと！
(More & More! Give us more voice!)
(ジャンプ＆ジャンプ！)高く高く！
(Jump & Jump! Higher and higher!)
まだ小さく微かだった声も
Even a voice that was still small and faint...
(ちょっとずつ)
(A little bit at a time)
確かに聞こえてきてんだよ
I could hear it clearly.
(いちにーさんはいっ！)
(One, two, three, go!)
はじめて触れてみてわかったの
I figured it out by finally touching it.
(今でも)
(Even now)
あなたに届いて欲しいこと
I want it to reach you.
(ホップ　ステップ　ジャンプ　はいっ！)
(Hop, step, jump, go!)
最初から最後まで
From the very beginning to the very end,
1秒だって逃さない
I won't miss a single second.
これだけは今だけはね
Just for now, only for now,
負けたくないの
I don't want to lose!
未来でも世界でも
Even in the future, even in the world,
今は変えられる気がするんだ
right now I feel like I can change things.
どこまで飛べるかな
Just how far can I fly?
今はちょっと想いのカケラ
Right now, just a little bit of the fragments of our thoughts,
もうちょっと足りなくても
even if they're still a bit not enough,
進みだした夢は
the dream that started moving forward...
あきらめない！やめたくない！
I won't give up! I don't want to stop!
あのねもっと(もっと)愛してくれるなら
Hey, if you love me more,
もっと(もっと)愛をあげる！
I'll give you more love!
あなたのハートをずっと
I'll hold your heart forever
はなさないから
and never let it go!
(モア＆モア！)声をもっと！
(More & More! Give us more voice!)
(ジャンプ＆ジャンプ！)高く高く！
(Jump & Jump! Higher and higher!)
(モア＆モア！)愛をもっと！
(More & More! Give us more love!)
(ジャンプ＆ジャンプ！)こんなもんじゃない！
(Jump & Jump! It's not enough!)
(モア＆モア！)声をもっと！
(More & More! Give us more voice!)
(ジャンプ＆ジャンプ！)高く高く！
(Jump & Jump! Higher and higher!)
(モア＆モア！)愛をもっと！
(More & More! Give us more love!)
(ジャンプ＆ジャンプ！)こんなもんじゃないぞ！
(Jump & Jump! It's not enough!)